Finding aid for University Herbarium (University of Michigan) Records, 1744-1745, 1851-1981, and 2001-2014
Bentley Historical Library
- Herbarium Historical Correspondence Collection, 1851-1971
  The Herbarium Historical Correspondence series, 1851-1971 (9.75 linear feet), arranged alphabetically by correspondent is a collection of historical botany-related correspondence as curated by the Herbarium. The Herbarium's original arrangement has been retained. The series includes correspondence by Herbarium faculty, Michigan botanists, and other notable American botanists. This series includes correspondence by University of Michigan School of Forestry director Charles A. Davis and University of Michigan Herbarium directors Calvin H. Kauffman and Edwin B. Mains. The series also includes correspondence by Herbarium founder Elizabeth Allmendinger, botany professor John Henry Ehlers, and curators Joyce Hedrick Jones, Bessie B. Kanouse, and Rogers McVaugh. Michigan botanists whose correspondence were collected by the Herbarium include Cecil Billington, Ernst A. Bessey (Professor of Mycology and Dean at Michigan State University), Emma J. Cole, Charles Keene Dodge (of the Michigan Geological and Biological Survey), and Clarence R. Hanes. In addition to Michigan botanists, the Herbarium collected papers of other leading botanical researchers. Represented names include Bruce Fink, leading lichenologist and chairman of the Miami University Department of Botany, Charles McIlvaine, Civil War veteran and leading mycologist, Charles H. Peck, the state botanist of New York, and Edward Tuckerman, a founding member of the Natural Historical Society of Boston. Other American botanists with records related to them include William Herbst, Howard A. Kelly, Charles E. Plitt, Paul Marshall Rea, and Edward B. Sterling.
  - Allmendinger, Elizabeth, 1866-1882
    - Allmendinger -- Brown, L., 1869-1874 (Box 28)
    - Clark, M.H. -- Cowles, S.N., 1869-1873 (Box 28)
    - Dubois, A. -- Frost, Mrs. Robert, 1867-1875 (Box 28)
    - Gillman, H. -- Hall, I.H., 1866-1875 (Box 28)
    - Harrington, M. -- Hunt, E., 1867-1882 (Box 28)
    - Lyons, A.B., 1872-1877 (Box 28)
    - Martindale, I.C. -- Patterson, H., 1872-1876 (Box 28)
    - Sanfrod, J. -- Spalding, V.M., 1867-1879 (Box 28)
    - Tuthill, T.H. -- Townsend, J.C., 1873-1874 (Box 28)
    - Vasey, G. -- White, C.D., 1871-1880 (Box 28)
    - Ann Arbor Scientific Association, 1875-1877 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1873-1879 (Box 28)
    - Notes, undated (Box 28)
  - Bessey, Ernest A., 1916-1923 (Box 28)
  - Billington, C., 1916-1931 (Box 28)
  - Cole, Emma J., 1893-1897 (Box 28)
  - Davis, Charles A., 1888-1904
    - Allen -- Atkinson, 1897-1902 (Box 28)
    - Bailey, L.H., 1891-1895 (Box 28)
    - Bain -- Blodgett, 1893-1901 (Box 28)
    - Britton, N. -- Butterfield, 1890-1902 (Box 28)
    - Calkins -- Dock, M.L. (plant specimen), 1894-1902 (Box 28)
    - Dodge, C.K. -- Eastbrook, 1890-1901 (Box 28)
    - Farr, G.A. -- Fox, W.F., 1892-1902 (Box 28)
    - Galloway, E.T. -- Gustin, H.K., 1891-1902 (Box 28)
    - Hall, J. -- Holzinger, 1891-1897 (Box 28)
    - Hubbard, L. -- Lamson-Scribner, 1896-1903 (Box 28)
    - Lane, Alfred, 1895-1901; 5 folders (Box 28)
    - Lemmon, J.G. -- Pettit, R.H., 1894-1903 (Box 28)
    - Michigan Academy -- Miscellaneous, 1892-1902 (Box 28)
    - Pingree, W.S. -- Rydberg, P.A., 1888-1904 (Box 28)
    - Sheldon, E.P. -- Snyder, J.L., 1892-1903 (Box 28)
    - Tarr, R.S. -- Wildey, E.A., 1891-1903 (Box 28)
  - Dodge, Charles Keene, Michigan Geological and Biological Survey, 1908-1923; 7 folders (Box 29)
  - Ehlers, John Henry (J.H.), 1917-1937
    - Anderson, E. -- Gleason, H.A., 1926-1934 (Box 29)
    - Hanes, Clarence R., 1933-1936 (Box 29)
    - Kenoyer -- Woolhiser, D., 1917-1937 (Box 29)
  - Fink, Bruce, 1906-1928 (Box 29)
  - Farwell, O.A., 1908 (Box 29)
    (correspondence with Charles Sprague Sargent)
  - Hanes, Clarence R., 1935-1955
    - Alexander -- Anderson, 1936-1941 (Box 29)
    - Bailey, L.H., lists of Rubus sent, undated (Box 29)
    - Bailey, L.H., 1937-1951; 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Ball -- Camp, 1936-1948 (Box 29)
    - Chase, Agnes, 1936-1947 (Box 29)
    - Clausen -- Darlington, 1938-1942 (Box 29)
    - Deam, Charles C., 1937-1949 (Box 29)
    - Drew-Hastings, 1935-1951 (Box 29)
    - Hermann, F.J. (U.S. Department of Agriculture), 1936-1955; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Hodgdon -- Ownbey, 1936-1955 (Box 29)
    - Palmer, Ernest J., 1936-1953 (Box 29)
    - Peattie -- Swallen, 1936-1945 (Box 29)
    - Tuthill-Yuncker, 1937-1947 (Box 29)
    - Notes, 1940-1955
      - Additions, Corrections, & Errata for Flora, 1947; 1946-1948 (Box 29)
      - Botanical observations, notes, etc., 1943-1947 (Box 29)
      - Congratulatory messages, book reviews, & clippings, 1947 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous Hanesiana: personal and biographical, 1940-1955 (Box 29)
  - Herbst, William, 1851-1912
    - Allison, Clara-Burt, Edward A., 1897-1901 (Box 29)
    - Dallas, Ellen -- Krout, A.F.K, 1887-1912 (Box 29)
    - Lloyd, C.G., 1895-1904; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Morgan, A.P. -- Williams, Thomas A., 1885-1905 (Box 29)
  - Historical miscellaneous correspondence, 1851-1911 (Box 29)
  - Holzinger, J.B., 1860 (Box 29)
  - Hoopes, Joshua, 1826 (Box 29)
  - Jones, Joyce Hedrick, 1890-1951
    - A-B, 1890-1950 (Box 29)
    - C-D, 1928-1950 (Box 29)
    - E-F, 1927-1950 (Box 29)
    - G-H, 1927-1951 (Box 29)
    - Herre, Albert W., 1939-1951 (Box 30)
    - Hughes, R.M., 1927-1928 (Box 30)
    - Identification lists, 1933-1938 (Box 30)
    - J-K, 1931-1950 (Box 30)
    - Kauffman, Calvin H., 1928 (Box 30)
    - L-M, 1927-1950 (Box 30)
    - Lepage, Ernest, 1930-1948 (Box 30)
    - Llano, George A., 1946-1951 (Box 30)
    - Mains, Edwin B., 1931-1935 (Box 30)
    - N-R, 1927-1951 (Box 30)
    - S, 1928-1951 (Box 30)
    - T, 1928-1950 (Box 30)
    - U-Z, 1926-1948 (Box 30)
  - Kanouse, Bessie, 1921-1959
    - A, 1930-1959 (Box 30)
    - B, 1926-1956 (Box 30)
    - Bonar, Lee, 1930-1956 (Box 30)
    - C, 1928-1958 (Box 30)
    - Cooke, William Bridge, 1936-1958 (Box 30)
    - D, 1946-1959 (Box 30)
    - E, 1931 (Box 30)
    - F, 1936-1956 (Box 30)
    - G, 1928-1958 (Box 30)
    - H, 1934-1959 (Box 30)
    - Hesler, L.R., 1928-1959 (Box 30)
    - J, 1944-1955 (Box 30)
    - Jackson, H.S., 1935-1951 (Box 30)
    - K (plant specimen), 1921-1957 (Box 30)
    - L, 1931-1959 (Box 30)
    - Lowe, Joe L., 1940-1958 (Box 30)
    - M, 1930-1957 (Box 30)
    - N, 1946-1950 (Box 30)
    - O, 1943-1956 (Box 30)
    - P, 1936-1960 (Box 30)
    - R, 1930-1956 (Box 30)
    - S, 1930-1956 (Box 30)
    - Seaver, Fred J., 1928-1948 (Box 30)
    - Smith, Alexander H., 1935-1956 (Box 30)
    - Stevenson, John A., 1929-1955 (Box 30)
    - Stewart, F.C., 1921-1930 (Box 30)
    - T, 1952-1959 (Box 30)
    - V, 1957-1959 (Box 30)
    - W-Z, 1925-1957 (Box 30)
  - Kauffman, Calvin H., 1906-1947
    - A, 1917-1930 (Box 31)
    - Archer, W.A., 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Arkless, Florence Oakes, 1921-1929 (Box 31)
    - Bal, S.N. -- Bisby, G.R., 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Black, H.B. -- Butler, E.W., 1920-1933 (Box 31)
    - Baxter, Dow. V., 1922-1927 (Box 31)
    - Benedict, Don, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Bessy, Ernst A., 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - Bonar, Lee, 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - Burnside, C.E., 1923-1930 (Box 31)
    - C., 1920-1932 (Box 31)
    - Cotner, F.B., 1921-1930 (Box 31)
    - D., 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - E, 1906-1931 (Box 31)
    - F, 1924-1930 (Box 31)
    - Fink, Bruce, 1920-1927 (Box 31)
    - Fink, Bruce, Acquisition of Bruce Fink Herbarium, 1927-1929 (Box 31)
    - Fitzpatrick, H.M., 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - G, 1921-1930 (Box 31)
    - Herbarium Equipment, 1921-1930 (Box 31)
    - Herbarium General, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Herbarium Library, 1921-1930 (Box 31)
    - H, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - J, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - K, 1906-1930 (Box 31)
    - Leonian, Leon H., 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - L, 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - Mc, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - M, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Mains, Edwin B., 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - Mexia, Ynes, 1925-1929 (Box 31)
    - Michigan, University of, general, 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - N, 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - O, 1920-1929 (Box 31)
    - P, 1920-1930 (Box 31)
    - Personal, 1907-1931; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Povah, Alfred H., 1920-1930 (Box 32)
    - R, 1920-1929 (Box 32)
    - Sartoris, George B., 1922-1930 (Box 32)
    - Sass, John, 1925-1932 (Box 32)
    - Sanbone, Ethel I. -- Sinnott, E.W., 1918-1933 (Box 32)
    - Skutch, A.F. -- Sturgis, William C., 1921-1930 (Box 32)
    - Schaeffer, Julius, 1926-1947 (Box 32)
    - Stevenson, John A., 1920-1929 (Box 32)
    - T-U-V, 1924-1929 (Box 32)
    - Thaxter, Ronald, 1920-1930 (Box 32)
    - Wehmeyer, L.E., 1922-1929 (Box 32)
    - Winters, Charles, 1923-1930 (Box 32)
    - W, 1921-1930 (Box 32)
    - Y-Z, 1922-1930 (Box 32)
  - Kelly, Howard A., 1910-1919 (Box 32)
  - Kreiger, L.L.C., 1910 (Box 32)
  - Livingston, Burton E., 1946 (Box 32)
  - McIlvaine, Charles, 1885-1909
    - A-D, 1893-1907 (Box 32)
    - E-H, 1893-1901 (Box 32)
    - Harshberger, John W., 1890-1908 (Box 32)
    - I-R, 1891-1901 (Box 32)
    - Peck, Charles H., 1893-1909; 5 folders (Box 32)
    - S-Z, 1885-1900 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1899-1901 (Box 32)
    - Field notes, 1898-1899 (Box 32)
  - McVaugh, Rogers, 1942-1971
    - Gaiser, Lulu O., 1950-1959 (Box 32)
    - Geiser, Samuel W., 1942-1960 (Box 32)
    - Gilly, Charles, 1955-1956 (Box 32)
    - Gonzalez-Rul, Judith, 1969-1971 (Box 32)
    - National Science Foundation, 1954-1961; 3 folders (Box 33)
    - Oklahoma, University Press, 1955-1967 (Box 33)
    - Senior, Robert M., 1952-1961 (Box 33)
    - Shacklette, Hansford T., 1959-1961 (Box 33)
    - Sherff, Earl E., 1952-1963 (Box 33)
    - Skutch, Alexander F., 1946-1964 (Box 33)
    - Svenson, Henry K., 1951-1960 (Box 33)
  - Mains, Edwin B., 1919-1962
    - A, 1920-1956 (Box 33)
    - Allen, Charles E., 1921-1931 (Box 33)
    - Arthur, Joseph C., 1932-1937 (Box 33)
    - Baggley, George F. to Bequaert, Joseph C., 1931-1952 (Box 33)
    - Biblio-Films to Butler, Karl D., 1931-1960 (Box 33)
    - Benedict, Don M., 1931-1938 (Box 33)
    - Bessey, Ernst A., 1931-1945 (Box 33)
    - Bonar, Lee, 1931-1956 (Box 33)
    - Brodie, Harold J., 1931-1950 (Box 33)
    - Brown, Clair A., 1924-1947 (Box 33)
    - Cain, Roy F. -- Christenson, M. B., 1928-1960 (Box 33)
    - Caldwell, Ralph M., 1928-1946 (Box 33)
    - Clausen, Robert T. -- Curry, D.P., 1925-1949 (Box 33)
    - Cotner, Frank B., 1931-1934 (Box 33)
    - Cummins, George B., 1927-1952 (Box 33)
    - Dale, E. E. -- Dayton, W.A., 1923-1952 (Box 33)
    - Dearness, John, 1925-1938 (Box 33)
    - Deam, Charles C. -- Dupias, G., 1921-1950 (Box 33)
    - Doak, K.D., 1932-1953 (Box 33)
    - Dodge, Carroll W., 1926-1954 (Box 33)
    - E, 1926-1942 (Box 34)
    - Eyerdam, Walter J., 1931-1942 (Box 34)
    - F, 1931-1950 (Box 34)
    - Fisher, George W., 1930-1959 (Box 34)
    - Fitzpatrick, Harry M., 1931-1944 (Box 34)
    - Gates, Frank C. -- Gregg, Clifford C., 1930-1962 (Box 34)
    - Griffin, C.W. -- Guyot, A. L., 1932-1948 (Box 34)
    - Gardner, Max W., 1931-1947 (Box 34)
    - Haddow, W. R. -- Herter, W. G., 1931-1943 (Box 34)
    - Higgens, Calvin E. -- Hutchinson, W. G., 1929-1953 (Box 34)
    - Herbarium equipment, 1935-1949 (Box 34)
    - Herbarium general, 1928-1936 (Box 34)
    - Herbarium library, 1931-1938 (Box 34)
    - Hesler, L.R. (Lexemuel Ray), 1931-1957 (Box 34)
    - Humphrey, H.B., 1931-1942 (Box 34)
    - I, 1934-1959 (Box 34)
    - J, 1934-1939 (Box 34)
    - Jackson, Herbert S., 1931-1949 (Box 34)
    - Johnston, C.O., 1931-1940 (Box 34)
    - K, 1923-1961 (Box 34)
    - L, 1930-1959 (Box 34)
    - Linder, David H., 1933-1945 (Box 34)
    - Lohman, Marion L., 1927-1941 (Box 34)
    - Lowe, Josiah L., 1929-1959 (Box 34)
    - Lundell, Cyrus L., 1932-1945 (Box 34)
    - M, 1930-1960 (Box 34)
    - Mc, 1932-1967 (Box 35)
    - McFarlin, James B., 1929-1935 (Box 35)
    - Martin, George W., 1931-1960 (Box 35)
    - Maxon, William R., 1930-1946 (Box 35)
    - Michigan, University of, general, 1920-1949 (Box 35)
    - Miller, Julian H.1931-1941 (Box 35)
    - N, 1930-1961 (Box 35)
    - O, 1928-1943 (Box 35)
    - P-Q, 1930-1950 (Box 35)
    - Personal, 1931-1938 (Box 35)
    - Povah, Alfred H., 1930-1951 (Box 35)
    - R, 1932-1958 (Box 35)
    - Rapp, Severin collections, 1922-1942 (Box 35)
    - Rogers, Donald P., 1937-1956 (Box 35)
    - St. John, Harold -- Singer, Rolf, 1931-1951 (Box 35)
    - Seaver, Fred J., 1931-1943; 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Smith, Alexander H., 1929-1949 (Box 35)
    - Sipe, Frank P. -- Soper, Richard S., Jr., 1921-1955 (Box 35)
    - Spahr & Glenn Co. -- Szent-Ivany, Joseph (J.J.H.), 1919-1960 (Box 35)
    - Steinhaus, Edward A., 1945-1961 (Box 35)
    - Steere, William C., 1931-1960 (Box 35)
    - Strong, Forrest C., 1929-1942 (Box 35)
    - Stevenson, John A., 1931-1959; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Swartz, Delbert, 1928-1934 (Box 35)
    - Sydow, Hans, 1922-1940 (Box 35)
    - Taylor, William Randolph, 1931-1949 (Box 36)
    - Tidd, Joseph S., 1931-1945 (Box 36)
    - U, 1920-1947 (Box 36)
    - U-V, 1930-1958 (Box 36)
    - Wagener, Willis W. -- West, C. J., 1931-1961 (Box 36)
    - West, Erdman -- Wiebe, G.A., 1931-1958 (Box 36)
    - Wiegand, Karl M. -- Wynne, Frances E., 1925-1955 (Box 36)
    - Weigel, Theodor O., 1929-1933 (Box 36)
    - Whetzel, Herbert H. (plant specimen), 1932-1944 (Box 36)
    - Y-Z, 1932-1948 (Box 36)
    - Zeller, Sanford M., 1920-1942 (Box 36)
  - Peck, Charles H., 1888-1912 (Box 36)
  - Plitt, Charles E., 1901 (Box 36)
  - Rea, Paul M., 1938-1948
    - Baxter, Dow V., 1942-1943 (Box 36)
    - Bonar, Lee, 1939-1945 (Box 36)
    - Coker, William C., 1938 (Box 36)
    - Long, William H., 1939-1943 (Box 36)
    - Granquist, Herbert, 1942 (Box 36)
    - Hagelstein, Robert, 1943-1944 (Box 36)
    - Howard, Grace E., 1943 (Box 36)
    - MacMillan, Howard G., 1939 (Box 36)
    - Miller, Vera, 1939-1942 (Box 36)
    - Missouri Botanical Garden, 1940-1943 (Box 36)
    - Morse, Elizabeth E., 1938-1946 (Box 36)
    - Murrill, W.A., 1945 (Box 36)
    - Overholds, L.O., 1944 (Box 36)
    - Seaver, Fred J., 1939-1944 (Box 36)
    - Singer, Rolf, 1943-1944 (Box 36)
    - Smith, Alexander H., 1939-1944 (Box 36)
    - Snell, Walter H., 1939-1943 (Box 36)
    - Stevenson, Shear & Edith Clements, 1944-1948 (Box 36)
    - Woodbury, Clifford A., Jr., 1940-1944 (Box 36)
    - Zeller, Sanford M., 1939-1943 (Box 36)
  - Sterling, Edward B., 1897-1916
    - Atkinson, Geo -- Killgore, Anthony, 1898-1916; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Lloyd Library -- Lloyd, Curtis Gates (C.G.), 1898-1912; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - McIlvaine, Charles, 1897-1905 (Box 36)
    - Peck, Charles H., 1898-1916; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Mason, L.B. -- Patterson, Flora, 1898-1910 (Box 36)
    - Pepper, G.W. -- Wright, Frank C., 1898-1911 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1915; 5 folders (Box 37)
  - Tuckerman, Edward, 1844-1853; 3 folders (Box 37)
    (Copies. Originals located in the American Antiquarian Society, Massachusetts)
- Herbarium Historical Photographs Collection, 1863-1981
  The Herbarium Historical Photographs series, 1863-1981 (0.5 linear feet), arranged alphabetically, is a collection of portraits and photographs of assorted botanists collected by the Herbarium. This series includes photographs of Michigan and non-Michigan botanists.
  - Anderson, E.G., 1922 (Box 37)
  - Appel, undated (Box 37)
  - Arden, W.A., circa 1930 (Box 37)
  - Arnold, Chester A., undated (Box 37)
  - Arnold, Ferdi, 1899 (Box 37)
  - Bartlett, Harley Harris, 1959 (Box 37)
  - Beal, William James, undated (Box 37)
  - Beaudslee, U.S. mycologist, 1948 (Box 37)
  - Belcher, Robert O., undated (Box 37)
  - Benninghoff, William S., 1980 (Box 37)
  - Bessey, Charles & Ernest, circa 1890-1944 (Box 37)
  - Billington, Cecil, 1941-1944 (Box 37)
  - Brotherton, Wilber, Jr., undated (Box 37)
  - Buck, William, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Campbell, Douglas Houghton, 1928 (Box 37)
  - Chang, Ying-Pe, undated (Box 37)
  - Chase, Agnes, 1953 (Box 37)
  - Cole, Emma J., undated (Box 37)
  - Cooper, Robert C., 1953 (Box 37)
  - Crum, Howard, 1954-1984 (Box 37)
  - Darlington, Henry Townsend, undated (Box 37)
  - Davis, Brodley Moore, 1942 (Box 37)
  - Deam, Charles C., 1923-1949 (Box 37)
  - Dodge, Charles K., 1907-1929 (Box 37)
  - Drew, William, 1951 (Box 37)
  - Drend, Evelyn, 1929 (Box 37)
  - Fields, William Grady, circa 1976 (Box 37)
  - Fife, Allan, 1979 (Box 37)
  - Futyma, Richard, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Group photographs, 1922-1955 (Box 37)
  - Gustafson, Felix G., undated (Box 37)
  - Hamel, Carel, 1930 (Box 37)
  - Kauffman, Calvin H., 1929-1953 (Box 37)
  - Keefs, Mrs. G & Dr. Paul Welch, undated (Box 37)
  - Koelz, Walter, undated (Box 37)
  - LaRue, Carl D., undated (Box 37)
  - Lowry, Robert J., circa 1940 (Box 37)
  - MacBride, Thomas Huston, undated (Box 37)
  - Madsen, Barbara, 1980 (Box 37)
  - McConnell, R.G., undated (Box 37)
  - McCrea, Adelia, 1940 (Box 37)
  - McIlvaine, Charles, circa 1900 (Box 37)
  - McVaugh, Rogers, 1962-1979 (Box 37)
  - Michigan botanists group photographs, 1922-1978 (Box 37)
  - Newcombe, Frederick C., 1920; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Nichols, George E., undated (Box 37)
  - Pippen, Richard, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Pollock, James B., undated (Box 37)
  - Smith, Alexander H., circa 1920-1981 (Box 37)
  - Spalding, Volney M., undated (Box 37)
  - Steere, James B., 1929 (Box 37)
  - Steere, William Campbell, 1939-1982; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Steiner, Erich, circa 1970 (Box 37)
  - Stowell, Louisa Reed, undated (Box 37)
  - Taylor, William Randolph, undated (Box 37)
  - U-M Department of Botany & Herbarium, 1863 (Box 37)
  - USDA Office of Drug & Poisonous Plant Investigations, 1912 (Box 37)
  - Von Wissmann, et al, undated (Box 37)
  - Voss, Edward A., 1980-1981 (Box 37)
  - Wagner, Warren H., Jr., undated
- Archived Website, 2010-2014
  The Archived Website series (2001-2014), documents the resources, events, people, and collections of the Herbarium. Content includes news, publications, collection policies, and research interests. This series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive. Starting in 2010, this website has been captured through the new program website on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
  - 2001-2008
    (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material)
  - 2008-2010
  - 2010-[2014]
Related Material
The Bentley Historical Library has a collection of Harley H. Bartlett papers received from the Bartlett estate. Bartlett's collections of botanical specimens can be accessed through the University of Michigan Herbarium. Bartlett's collections of Batak manuscripts and other anthropological materials can be accessed through the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology and the American Philosophical Society.
Additional archival material related to the historical correspondence collected by the Herbarium can be found in several archives.
A collection of Emma J. Cole's papers and botanical specimens is located in the Grand Rapids Public Museum (Accession no. 2008.43.1).
Collections for Ernst A. Bessey are located at the Michigan State University archives (Index no. UA17.5 and 00116).
Collections related to Edward Tuckerman are available through the American Antiquarian Society and the Amherst College Archives (Call no. MA.00043).
A collection of Charles E. Plitt's papers are available at the USDA's National Agricultural Library's special collections
A collection of Clarence R. Hanes papers is available at Western Michigan University (call no. A-81).